Sutherland - Sydney 0478 775 449 - chrispaivamail@gmail.com www.chrispaiva.com

SUMMARY

User experience designer with vast experience in designing online products and multi-device platforms for various sectors and industries, including e-commerce, e-learning and fintech. Designing user experiences for well-established brands such as McDonald's, Johnson & Johnson, PayPal and PagSeguro. For examples of my work view my portfolio: www.chrispaiva.com.









SKILLS AND TOOLS

- Conducting user research and usability tests
- Wireframing and prototyping (Axure, Sketch)
- Delivering UX design artefacts: user flows, user journeys, personas, site maps, functional specification documents
- UI and visual design (Adobe Creative Cloud Photoshop, Illustrator and InDesign)
- Applying Agile methodologies: Scrum and Kanban
- Formatting and optimising web pages using HTML, CSS and SEO
- Data analytics and marketing (Omniture, HubSpot)

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Freelancer UX/UI Designer – Guroo Producer (Sydney / Australia)

Jun 2017 to present date

- My role involves designing and specifying the platform on which users can create their own e-learning content.
- As a remote worker, I also provide my team with UX design artefacts, such as user flows, site maps, and functional specification documents to guide them throughout the development.

UX/UI Designer – Workstar (Sydney / Australia)

December 2014 to May 2017

- Leading UX designer at Workstar one of Australia's top eLearning companies, offering a complete range of learning experiences, content development and digital platform delivery solutions.
- My role involved designing e-learning training tools and platforms for clients including McDonald's Australia, Johnson & Johnson and PayPal. These platforms assist clients improve their training, sales and brand engagement. Through the UX design process I led discovery sessions, user surveys, focus groups, journey maps, card sorting and usability tests with stakeholders and users.

Senior Product Analyst – UOL (São Paulo / Brazil)

March 2013 to July 2014

- Part of the product management team of PagSeguro. PagSeguro is the number one Brazilian website focused in online/mobile payments and is part of UOL Groupsimilar to PayPal;
- My role as a product analyst was to create new features for the product, at the same time improving users' experience and satisfaction, taking into consideration previous and current user research findings, business needs, and market opportunities. I worked directly with the UX/UI team, software developers, and business area.

Senior UX Designer – UOL (São Paulo / Brazil)

November 2010 to March 2013

- Part of the UOL UX team, working specifically on **PagSeguro** number one Brazilian website focused in online/mobile payments and is part of **UOL Group**;
- My role as a UX designer involved designing the company's online payment solution (www.pagseguro.com.br), focusing in improving the user experience in their administrative view, website and checkout experience.

UX Designer – Catho Online (São Paulo / Brazil)

December 2008 to November 2010

- Catho Online is the number one Brazilian website focused in jobs, employment, career, and recruitment;
- My role as a UX designer was to improve the user experience throughout the platform, including user profile (resume), job search, and checkout experience.

VOLUNTARY WORK

Ultimo Community Centre (Sydney / Australia)

October 2014 to December 2014

 Volunteered at the centre by helping to create newsletters and printable posters to promote upcoming activities.

EDUCATION

FIAP, **2013** (São Paulo / Brazil) MBA (focus on Project Management)

UNAERP, 2007 (São Paulo / Brazil) Bachelor of Marketing and Advertising